AINAM JEAN-PAUL

Phone: (+86)13258268103 jpainam@gmail.com jpainam@uacosendai-edu.net University of Electronic Science and Technology of China Qinshuihe Campus, Chengdu Sichuan 611731, China

Quality-focused software specialist. Well-versed in several programming languages with three years' experience in the field of teaching. Proficient communication, leadership and project management abilities.

EDUCATION

PhD University of Electronic Science and Technology of China

Sept 2017 - Now

Interest: Computer Vision – Neural Network

GPA: 3.56/4 (89/100)

MSc Babcock University; Nigeria

Nov 2012 – Jun 2014

Major: Computer Science

CGPA: 4.45/5 (90/100) - Highest CGPA in the department

BSc Cosendai Adventist University; Cameroon

Oct 2009 – Aug 2012

Major: Software Engineering

CGPA: 82.25/100 (Highest CGPA in the school)

COMPUTER SKILLS

Programming: Java, C/C++, Python, JavaScript, PHP

Platform: Windows, Linux (Debian, Ubuntu)

Network: Network Administrator, Routing & Switching

HONORS AND AWARDS

Second Class Honor 2014 First Class Honor 2012

Full Scholarship for Academic Achievement

2012

Scholarship for outstanding student from Cosendai University to pursue an MSc degree

EXPERIENCE

Cosendai Adventist University, Cameroon

Sept 2014 to Aug 2017

Assistant Lecturer, Computer Science Department

- Data Structure (C, C++)
- Object Oriented Programming (Java)
- Web Design and Web Application (JavaScript, PHP, Symfony, CodeIgniter)

CFAOSKILLS - CFAO EQUIPMENT

Jan 2017 – Sep 2017

Software development for the training department.

In charge of the User Experience and Human Interaction Design (Java, Hibernate, HSQLDB)

Adventist Development Relief Agency (ADRA CHAD)

Jun 2014 – Aug 2014

Website design, computer maintenance and Network Administration

SoftCabin – Babcock University

Jan 2014 – Jun 2014

Software development for archiving documents.

In charge of designing a uniform and generic model for querying and accessing the database (Java, Hibernate, MySQL)

Academic Internship at Cosendai Adventist University

School Management System. In charge of the Request Management module (PHP, JavaScript, MySQL)

SELECTED PUBLICATIONS

Jean-Paul Ainam, Ke Qin, Guangchun Luo "Sparse Label Smoothing Regularization for Semi-Supervised Person Re-Identification" IEEE Access 2018.

Jean-Paul Ainam, Ke Qin, Guangchun Luo "Person Re-Identification through Clustering and Partial Label Smoothing Regularization" ACM International Conference on Big Data and Smart Computing; Bali, Indonesia.

Jean-Paul Ainam, YA Adekunle, AK Adjo "An Improved Bayesian Filtering Technique for Spam Recognition" International Journal of Advanced Research in Computer Science 2013

CERTIFICATION - PROFESSIONAL TRAINING

Cisco Certified Network, CCNA & CCNP; Cisco Academy, July 2013 Certification Verification No. 414694170760EOWK CISCO ID No. CSCO12399754

LANGUAGES

French: Native Language

English: Intermediate Listener and Speaker, Advanced Reading and Writing

Arabic: Intermediate Listener

REFERENCES

Prof QIN KE, PhD; Supervisor

University of Electronic Science and Technology of China (UESTC), Chengdu School of Computer Science & Engineering qinke@uestc.edu.cn

Tel: 138 - 80363890

Dr Esso Christian, PhD; Mentor

Vice-Rector in charge of Student Affairs Cosendai University, Cameroon pstesso@yahoo.fr

Tel: +237678829348